Gloria Ho

Web Developer

Forest Hills, NY (646) 535 - 3215 gloria@gloria-ho.com linkedin.com/in/gloria-ho github.com/gloria-ho gloria-ho.com

Hard working web developer with a strong background in management, a newfound passion for programming, and the ability to build a web presence from concept and design to writing code. Since 2016,a self-directed learner, regular attendee of tech meetups and hackathons, and an open-source project contributor. Free time is spent self teaching French, travelling, tinkering with fountain pens, knitting, and volunteering.

Technical Skills

Ruby / Ruby on Rails JavaScript jQuery Python

Sass / CSS Bootstrap HTML5 PostgreSQL / MySQL

Git Bash **REST APIs** AJAX

Technical Projects

Travel Tracker Web App

Rails, PostgreSQL, User Authentication, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

- User can create and manage trip itineraries and funds.
- User can create and manage group members to attach to trips.

Book Search Web App (contributor) Rails, PostgreSQL, User Authentication, JavaScript, API, AJAX

- User can search for and read previews for books, as well as read and write reviews.
- User can add, edit, and delete book progress to profile.

Admin Panel Web App

Rails, PostgreSQL, User Authentication, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

- Administrator can create, view, edit, and delete data.
- Groups of cohorts are created by joining data from the class, teacher, and student tables.

R-umblr Blog Website

Sinatra, PostgreSQL, User Authentication, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

- User management and restricted access via user authentication.
- User can read, write, edit, and delete blog entries.

Pokedex Website

JavaScript, API, ¡Query, AJAX, Bootstrap, Sass

Responsive design with animations, pulls and displays data from an external API.

Movie Info Website

Python, HTML5, CSS

Responsive website that displays movie information and trailers from an external source.

Education

New York Code + Design Academy, New York, NY Udacity, Udacity.com

LaGuardia Community College, LIC, NY

Software Engineering Intensive Intro Into Programming Nanodegree 30 Credits / Commercial Photography 2005 - 2006

Experience

Assistant Manager

Binex Line Corp., Fort Lee, NJ

01/2010 - 08/2016

2018

2017

- Significantly increased productivity and efficiency by developing new training procedures
- Led an import/sales team of 5 employee
- Managed accounting as well as high profile clients

Assistant Manager

Worldwide Axcess, New York, NY

09/2008 - 12/2009

• Coordinated projects from conception/design to proofing/manufacturing and import/distribution for high profile accounts including Coty, Estee Lauder, Bacardi, and Warner

Assistant Manager

Momofuku Restaurant, New York, NY

07/2006 - 08/2008

Oversaw schedules, payroll, accounting, and HR and organized the opening of new branches